别了
Bye.
我想单独待着...
I... I want to be alone...
跟我妻子一起
with my wife.
我是个自私的混蛋
I'm a selfish S.O.B.
我没能带你去里约热内卢...
I... I never got you to rio.
店里总是...
There was always...
有层出不穷的问题
one more problem at the stores.
你该过更美好的人生
You deserve better than that.
我爱你
I love you.
一直爱着你
I always have.
- 我准备好了abc- 没事的
- I'm ready.abc- It's okay.
我知道...
I know...
来人啊...
Somebody...
救救她!
Help her!
54岁女性 出现急性呼吸衰竭
54-year-old woman withabcacute respiratory failure.
无过敏 肺部正常 无气管损伤
No anaphylaxis,lungabcissues,or tracheal lesions.
毒性检测abc没有可卡因或安非他明残留
Tox screen was clean forabccoke and amphetamines.
我能说出30个可能abc每个都足以引起呼吸骤停 会厌发炎
I will give you 30 reasons,one for each pound thatabccaused the apnea which enflamed the epiglottis.
咱们彩虹联盟中棕色皮肤和双性恋那两位abc咋都不在?
Why is our rainbow coalitionabcmissing brown and bi?
13看着病人 Kutner的狗病了
Thirteen's with a patient,andabckutner's dog's sick.
午饭前他应该能来
He should be in by lunch.
这不是呼吸骤停abc她睡觉的时候好着呢
No apnea because no sleepingabcproblems when she's sleeping.
她这半年以来都在照料她丈夫abc他丈夫心力衰竭 时日无多
She spent the last six months caring forabcher husband who's dying of heart failure.
第31个可能 重创她丈夫心脏的元凶abc也重创了她的气管
Reason 31--whatever whacked the husband'sabcheart is also whacking her airway.
而且 谢天谢地 我还以为abcKutner是回家疗伤去了呢
And... oh,good. I thought maybe kutnerabcwas home nursing the rib you broke
上次的病例 你抢功劳的时候abc真是在他背后狠狠给了一刀啊
when you elbowed your way inabcfor credit on the last patient.
我帮了大忙
I contributed.
那病人的病因也不是来自她丈夫abc除非肺癌也能传染
And the patient's illness wasn't caused byabcher husband unless lung cancer's contagious.
真有意思 不过不是说病例abc那挺无聊的
Interesting. Not about theabcpatient. That was kinda dull.
我原以为你是为了掩护Kutner才说谎的abc这听上去还蛮高尚
I thought maybe you were lying toabccover for kutner,which sounds noble,
但实际上你是因为愧疚 而非出于友情
except you're doing it outabcof guilt instead of love.
大约半年前 他丈夫得病之前abc她去夏威夷看望过她妹妹
She visited her sister in hawaii about sixabcmonths ago,just before her husband got sick.
有可能在某个岛上感染了类鼻疽
Could've picked up melioidosisabcfrom one of the islands.
然后传染她老公abc把他和他弱小的免疫系统都放倒了
Would have jumped to the husband andabcfinished off him and his lame immune system.
无肿瘤 无药物残留 无细菌
No tumors,no drugs,no bacteria.
只剩病毒这一种可能--水痘
Leaves viral--abcvaricella zoster.
给她用阿昔洛韦 静脉输液
Start her on iv fluids and acyclovir.
办不到 她要求出院照看她丈夫
Can'T. She's demanding to be releasedabcso she can get home to her husband.
多么甜蜜动人啊abc他们俩可以死在一块了
How sweet. They can die together.
不用前后相差40年分开死了
Instead of separately,40 years apart.
她说她呼吸骤停的时候abc他病情似乎有好转
She claims he got strongerabcas soon as she stopped br
精神刺激确是一剂良药
The mind can heal the body.
看到自己老婆痛苦abc真有可能延缓他死亡呢
Seeing his wife in distress mightabchave actually slowed down his death.
不然就是他意识到自己快要恢复单身了abc于是肾上腺素暴涨
Or he just had an adrenaline surge when heabcsaw his chance to hit the singles' market.
- 送她回家abc- 不一定非这样
- Send her home.abc- We don't need to.
我有主意... 我自己想出来的
I had an idea... all by myself.
- Eddie?abc- 他刚刚在大厅里游荡
- Eddie?abc- Found him loitering in the lobby.
你还陪着我呢
You're still with me.
我这副衰样 还能上哪去呢?
Where the hell else am I gonna go?
若你允许的话 我们准备治好你
And now,with your permission,we'dabclike to try to make you better.
表演还有一小时就要开始了
The pageant starts in an hour.
你得帮帮忙
You have to do something.
她脑袋好像出问题了
There's something wrong inside her head.
完全搞不清楚周围的状况
It's like she has no ideaabcwhat's going on around her.
我还当她是挑逗我呢
I thought she was just flirting with me.
我能搞定 但得花你三块七毛五分钱
I can fix it,but it'sabcgonna cost you... $3.75.
这咖啡我才不肯白给你呢
I'm not just gonna give you my coffee.
就当这是哥斯达黎加醒酒果汁吧
Think of it as costa rican sober juice.
她喝醉酒了?
She's drunk?
有一丝清新的薄荷味 隐藏在玫瑰香水
That little minty scent hidingabcbeneath the rose petal perfume
樱桃花保湿面霜和晨露般发胶的香气下
and the cherry blossom moisturizerabcand the morning dew hair spray.
你溜到妈妈的盥洗室里abc灌了杯她的漱口水?
You sneak into mommy's bathroomabcand gulp some of her mouthwash?
感觉棒极了
Gotta be perfect.
你吐出来了么?
You spit it out?
妈妈都不吐出来
Mommy doesn'T.
治疗见效了 Charlotte的呼吸abc恢复正常 她可以出院了
Treatment worked. Charlotte's breathing'sabcback to normal. She's being discharged.
她又能继续给丈夫守夜了abc他又快不行了
She can resume her vigil over herabchusband who started fading again.
有所得 必有所失嘛
Win some,lose some.
而严格来说 他又不是我的病人abc所以我们大有所得
And strictly speaking,sinceabche's not my patient,win some.
瞧 这都几点了abc比Taub为Kutner撒的谎还迟了半小时
Look at the time. It's half pastabc"taub was lying about kutner."
他可能又去了个漫画节abc找了个神奇女侠共度良宵
He probably wentto a comic book fest,spentabcthe night at some wonder woman's lair.
- 他应该...abc- 查明他在干嘛 或者在干谁
- I'm sure he'll-- - Findabcout what or who he's doing.
无论如何 Cuddy终究会要我abc在"解雇理由"上写明的
Either way,cuddy's gonna want me toabcwrite it under "reason for termination."
- 是Kutner么?abc- 是Charlotte
- That kutner?abc- Charlotte.
氧饱和度和ST正常 不是气管的问题
02 sat and s-t are normal.abcIt's not her airway.
- 你没事?abc- 别惦记我了 她正疼呢
- You're okay.abc- Don't worry about me. She's in pain.
脉动有力 脉速正常
Pulse is rabid and regular.
- 肺部没有积水abc- 怎么回事?
- No fluid in her lungs.abc- What's happening?
我不知道
I don't know.
Kutner 是Foreman和13 开门啊
Kutner. It's foreman and thirteen.
你往哪走?
Where are you going?
House可不是要查明他不在哪里
House didn't ask us toabcfind out where he wasn'T.
你要是想顺着防火梯爬到五楼...
If you wanna climb aabcfifth floor fire escape...
这样会快些
This might be faster.
Kutner
Kutner.
果真是男孩和男人的天堂啊
Man/boy heaven.
难怪他不想出门呢
Surprised he ever leaves.
日程表上什么都没有
There's nothing on his calendar.
他的寻呼机还在这
His pager's still here.
哦 天啊
Oh,god.
赶紧派辆救护车来abcWillis街410号 5楼C座
I need an ambulance atabc410 willis,apartmen5c.
28岁男子 一枪正中右太阳穴
28-year-old male. Singleabcgunshot wound to the right temple.
没有脉搏!
No pulse!
通知Princeton医院 请外伤部门人员就位
Alert princeton plainsboro.abcHave a trauma unit ready.
瞳孔已扩大 头部肿胀
His pupils dilated. His head's swollen.
- 还是没有脉搏 醒醒啊 Kutner!abc- 让我试试
- Still no pulse. Come on,kutner!abc- Let me try.
他全身冰冷
He's cold.
Eric!
他什么都没说...跟谁都没说
He didn't say anything... to any of you.
家庭问题...
Family problems...
感情问题 经济压力?
bad relationship,financial pressures?
他双亲曾在他眼前被杀
His parents wereabcshot right in front of him.
这都是几百年前的事了
Parents are ancient history.
要是真在意的话 就不会淡忘
Not to someonewho actually cares.
他不是割脉...
He didn't slit his wrists and...
不是静静地离去 他是用枪
peacefully driftabcaway--he shot himself.
也没写遗书
He didn't leave a note.
说明极度恐慌
That means panic.
要是每周共事80小时的那些笨蛋abc有所察觉的话 这本是可以避免的
Which could have been preempted if the idiots whoabcworked alongside him for 80 hours a week had seen this coming.
你是在怪我们?
You're blaming us?
只是想搞明白
Just trying to figure it out.
如果他曾求助的话abc我们当然会帮忙 但他没有
We would have helped himif heabchad reached out to us. He didn'T.
我们应当有所察觉
We should have picked up on something.
这不是我们的错!
This isn't our fault!
四分之一的自杀者abc都从来不将苦闷外露
Something like 25% of suicidal peopleabcshow no outward signs of depression.
不对
No.
四分之一的自杀者身边只有abc漠不关心 不愿负疚的朋友
25% of suicidal people have friends whoabcdidn't notice anything and don't want to feel guilty.
自杀相当于毁掉一切可能abc所以Kutner是大笨蛋
Killing himself also kills allabcother options,makes kutner an idiot.
深感遗憾 那是当然的abc因此内疚 毫无道理
So pity,yes,but guilt,no.
这不过是自我安慰罢了
That's what you wanna tell yourself.
我们手上还有个病人呢abc确切地说 有两个
We still have a patient. Actually,two.
一个病情恶化abc另一个病情应当恶化
One worsening,one whoabcshould be worsening.
你不是在同时否认abcKutner和那老公的现实吧
You can't be in denial aboutabckutner and the husband.
Eddie是以精神支撑着生命abc这也不是不可能
It's possible eddie's body isabcwilling itself to live.
这种奇闻 留给小报吧
Well,call the tabloids.
跟他们说你刚刚目睹了abc肾功能小小增强的奇迹
Tell them you just witnessed the miracleabcof slightly increased kidney function.
也许我们该把这病例abc移交给别的医生
Maybe we should pass thisabcfile off to another doctor.
下个病例呢 也移交?
And the next one too?
那再下个病例呢?
The one after that?
要移交多少个病例 你们才能abc接受Kutner死了这个现实?
How many files till it'sabcokay that kutner's dead?
从心肌酶来看 她没有心脏病发作
Cardiac enzymes means sheabcdidn't have a heart attack.
视觉正常 说明没有线粒体疾病
No vision problems means noabcmitochondrial disease.
可能是代谢紊乱 酸毒症
Could be a metabolic disorder,acidosis.
血液酸碱值很正常
Blood ph was normal.
多浆膜炎能使会厌附近的薄膜发炎
Polyserositis would inflame theabcmembranes near her epiglottis
心包膜发炎 使胸口疼痛
and the heart'sabcpericardium,causing the chest pain.
我很惋惜
I'm sorry.
我雇了一位悲痛心理咨询师abc我敢说你们都不会去看
I've hired a grief counselorabcwhom I'm sure none of you will see,
我也准你们假abc但我敢说你们也都不会要
and I'm offering time off,whichabcI'm sure none of you will take.
记得有这些选择就好
But just know it's available.
符合多浆膜炎症状 给她用消炎痛
Polyserositis fits.abcStart her on indomethacin.
- 如果你不想处理这个病例...abc- 我没事...
- If you'd rather not deal with this case...abc- I'm fine...
不管Wilson会怎么说
despite what wilson will say.
他还没来找过你?
He hasn't come to you?
我很确定他周二早上要搓麻将来着
Pretty sure he hasabcmah-jongg tuesday mornings.
我猜想abc他是觉得我自个儿解决更好
I assume he thinks Iabcwill work through this better
没了他给我拼命插翅膀abc我没准还能飞得更高
if I don't have to keepabcflicking his wings off my shoulder.
你一点概念也没有?
You didn't even have an inkling?
我知道abc他心中的橄榄球梦之队土崩瓦解了
I know his fantasyabcfootball team cratered.
还以为他已经承受过来了
Figured he'd gotten over it.
那...
Well...
对你的损失深表遗憾
sorry for your loss.
多谢 但我没啥损失
Thanks. But it's not my loss.
那就为你这么想深表遗憾
Then I'm sorry you don't think it is.
病人的膜组织可没法自愈
Patient's membranes aren'tabcgonna heal themselves.
Taub去进行治疗了
Taub went to run the treatment.
我们想去见Kutner的父母
We'd like to go see kutner's parents.
我也去
I'll join you.
多浆膜炎损伤组织和器官外abc包裹着的保护性薄膜
Polyserositis damages the protectiveabccovering around tissue and organs.
消炎痛就是种消炎药 能治好这种病
The indomethacin is simply anabcanti-inflammatory,but it should fix it.
只要别再疼了就成
Just make the pain stop.
Charlotte...
闭上眼睛
close your eyes.
快闭上...
Now...
想象自己...
pretend you...
终于去到里约热内卢了
finally made it down to rio.
正站在阳台上...
You're on the balcony of A...
在一家豪华宾馆阳台上
some fancy hotel.
你从没这样甜言蜜语过
You never talk like this.
你就... 别说话 让我来说
Yeah,just... shut up and let me do this.
你站在阳台上 看盛大的游行
And you're on that balcony,andabcyou're watching the mardi gras.
那叫嘉年华
It's called carnival.
如果不能跟你一起 我哪也不想去
And I don't wanna go without you.
我要你去
I want you to.
我要你成就你梦想过的一切
And I want it to beabceverything you've ever dreamed of.
很抱歉打扰了...abc但我得再做个检查...
Sorry to interrupt... but I'dabclike to run one more test...
给你做
on you.
这是我们领养他的第一天abc他那时才6岁
This is the first dayweabcgot him. He was six.
绝对是你见过最教人疼爱的小孩
Sweetest little boy you ever met.
他应该挺害怕的...
Must have been scary...
刚刚经历过悲恸abc又被交给一个陌生的家庭
going through a trauma and thenabcbeing handed off to a new family.
我们一直让他叫我们Richard和Juliaabc但他总是叫Kutner先生 太太
We kept telling him to call us richard andabcjulia,but it was always mr. And mrs. Kutner.
在他9岁生日的时候abc我们送了他一套化学用具
And on his ninth birthday,weabcgave him a chemtry set.
Lawrence一直喜欢把东西炸飞
Lawrence always loved blowing things up.
那时他说 "谢谢妈妈 谢谢爸爸"
And he said,"thanks,mom. Thanks,dad."
从那时起 我们就是他爸爸妈妈了
That's who we were from then on.
他非常特别
He was pretty special.
曾与他共事 我们深感荣幸
We were lucky to have him.
你们与他一起的时间最长
You spent the most time with him.
他对你们所有人都赞誉有加
He spoke so highly of all of you.
你们知道这是为什么吗?
Do you have any idea?
我们也很想知道 我们...
Wish weabcdid.We all--
是名字的问题
It was his name.
他很矛盾abc不知哪里有自己的容身之地
He was conflicted,didn'tabcknow where he fit in.
被强行抽离自己的生活abc跟你们扯到一块
Being ripped out of hisabcworld and stuck into yours.
我们一向鼓励他abc保持自己民族的传统
We encouraged him toabchold on to his heritage.
当每个人都叫你Lawrence Kutner时abc很难把自己看作Lawrence Choudhary
It's hard to still be lawrence choudharyabcwhen everyone sees you as lawrence kutner.
是他提出随我们姓的
It was his idea to take our name.
- 你们应该拒绝abc- House
- Then you should have said no.abc- House.
他的英文姓氏使他混淆了自己的身份
All his anglo name gave him was theabcillusion that he was someone he wasn't.
你们只从感性而没有理性考量
You were being emotional,not rational.
你们根本不了解他
You didn't understand him.
我们爱这个孩子 你这王八蛋
We loved that boy,you son of a bitch.
你们希望他快乐abc于是把他的痛苦拦在门外
You wanted to make him happyabcby shutting out his pain.
表面看来他很快乐abc你们以为痛苦消失了
When he looked happy,youabcassumed the pain had gone.
其实是隐藏得更深了...
It just got buried deeper...
他苦苦挣扎于自己的身份abc直至把一颗子弹射进--
leaving him tormented about who heabcwas until finally he put a bullet--
House!
回医院去
Go back to the hospital.
我为你们儿子的死感到遗憾
I'm sorry about your son.
消炎药不起作用 她还是痛abc排除多发性浆膜炎
Indomethacin had no effect. She'sabcstill in pain. Rules out polyserositis.
我给Eddie做了个荷尔蒙测试abc促乳素高于正常水平
I ran a hormone panel on eddie.abcHis prolactin's above normal.
就是说他正在好转
Means he's actually improving.
很多因素会引起人体化学状态改变--
Body chemistry changes forabcall sorts of reasons--
压力 恐惧-- 为什么爱不可以?
stress,fear--whyabcnot love?
也许他就这么好起来了
But maybe he's goingabcinto some sort of remission.
你没问我有没有abc从Kutner家看出了什么端倪
You haven't asked if I learnedabcanything relevant from the kutners.
如果你看出来了 我想你会主动说的
If you had,I'm sure you'dabchave mentioned it.
或者你害怕真有什么和他的死有关
Or you're just afraid thereabcis something relevant.
这意味着 你原本可以挽救他的生命
Which would mean youabccould have saved him.
我不认为 人们选择自杀abc就是为了寻求他人帮助
I don't buy that suicide isabcalways a cry for help.
有时 你根本不想别人帮你
Sometimes you just don't want help.
幸亏当初有人拉你一把...
Good thing you got some...
不然你会再度寻死abc而且不会失手...
or you'd have triedabcagain and gotten it right.
她没得韦格纳肉芽肿
She doesn't have wegener'S.
肾功能正常 不是棉尘症
Kidney function's normal.abcIt's not byssinosis.
也不是心二尖瓣狭窄abc所有诊断都不符合
It's not mitral valveabcstenosis. Nothing fits.
如果所有诊断都不符合
If it doesn't fit any diagnosis...
那就只剩下一个原因
it just leaves one diagnosis.
我是House医生 你得了肥厚性心肌病
I'm dr. House. You haveabchypertrophic cardiomyopathy.
他的心脏太弱 你的则太强abc好消息是 这是可治愈的
His heart is too weak. Yours is tooabcstrong. Good news is it's fixable.
我们引发一次心脏病abc然后杀死多余的肌肉
We induce a massive heart attackabcand kill off the extra muscle.
你要使我心脏病发作?
You wanna give me a heart attack?
只有在心脏大小正常情况下abc才会有危险
It's only dangerous ifabcyour heart is normal size.
- 但既然--abc- 你说真的吗?
- But since all the--abc- Are you serious?
假的
No.
实在很让人郁闷
This is actually very annoying,
我已经厌倦了靠撒谎abc来威吓病人说出真话
and I'm getting really bored of lying toabcpatients to scare them into telling me the truth.
她在装病
She's faking.
如果她再装下去abc接下来的治疗方法会杀死她
And yes,if she keeps faking,I'm going toabceventually do something that will kill her.
那为什么...她的气管是怎么回事?
How could she be... the wind pipe thing?
那是真的 治疗使她好转了
That was real. Treatmentabcmade her better.
但她好转了你就会恶化abc所以她继续装病
But good for her was bad for you,whichabcwas bad for her,so she made herself bad.
就这么简单
It's all so simple.
她发现她病得越厉害abc你就撑得越久
She figured the sicker sheabcwas,the longer you'd hang on.
Charlotte?
我们很多年没这么亲近了
We haven't been this close for years.
我希望能一直这样
I wanted to hang onto that.
拜托 你没听过狼来了吗
Oh,please. People hate reruns.
是我的腿 我发誓这次是真的
It's my leg. I swear this is real!
你要上吊赌咒呢 还是拉钩发誓？因为--
What,you pinky swear,or youabcjust plain swear?Because--
她怎么装得了这个?
How can she fake that?
装不了
She can't.
那么...什么会撕裂会厌abc并且让肌肉消失?
So... what can shred an epiglottisabcand make muscle disappear?
Kutner先生和Kutner太太
Mr. And mrs. Kutner.
他们既然能害死Kutnerabc为什么不能害死Charlotte?
They caused kutner'sabcdeath. Why not charlotte's?
哀悼期结束 Foreman回复刻薄本色
Mourning period's over.abcForeman's sense of irony is back.
我错了 种族困惑不会立刻致死
I was wrong about the ethnic reason.
第1步-- 先把姓名改回去
Step one--change your name back.
第2步-- 如果第1步失败abc搬到班加罗尔 (印度城市)
Step two--if step oneabcfails,move to bangalore.
第14步-- 如果13步失败 才是自杀
Step 14--if step 13 doesn'tabcwork,kill yourself.
怎么-- 你打算把他通讯录上的人abc都奚落一遍 直至找出答案?
So what now--you gonna insult your way throughabchis rolodex till you find someone with an answer?
我很客气地打给他的朋友abc全都帮不上忙
I've been polite to the friends I'veabccalled,all of whom were useless.
他们并非帮不上忙abc只是知道的不比我们多
They weren't useless. They justabcdidn't know anything more than we did.
还不是一样
Tomato,tomah-to.
多发性硬化病 髓鞘脱失abc影响神经传导
M.S. Weakens myelinabcsheath,compromises nerve conduction.
我说的是Charlotteabc还有救的那一位
I'm talking about charlotte,theabcone who's still alive.
你们俩 把她塞入MRIabc确定是否多发性硬化
You two,stick her inabcan mri. Confirm M.S.
你 去给Eddie做个超声abc反正你正盘算背着我做
And you run the echo on eddie thatabcyou're planning to do behind my back
看他的心脏有没有好转
toee if his heart's improving.
你居然让我雇一个变态?
Did you let me hire a pervert?
要是我自己雇了而不让你雇abc岂不太虚伪了
Well,it would hypoitical of me not to.
这是Kutner的警方记录调查
Kutner's police background checkabcfrom when he started.
他曾被控以不恰当露体罪
He was charged with indecent exposure.
Kutner在宾夕法尼亚对阵达特茅斯abc的橄榄球赛中脱光了衣服
Kutner streaked atabcthe penn-dart mouth football game.
在你心目中 他不正是会这样做的人吗?
Precisely the kind ofabcthing you'd expect him to do.
不要紧的 你觉得难过是应该的
It's okay. You should be upset.
他像你一样思考abc像你一样挑战极限
He thought like you,pushedabcboundaries like you.
如果他想我一样思考...
If he thought like me...
他就会知道 活得再痛苦abc也比死了强那么一点点
he wouldave known that living in miseryabcsucks marginally less than dying in it.
再忍耐一下 很快就能abc回到Eddie身边了
Just a few more minutes,thenabcwe'll get you back to eddie.
30年来和同一个男人在一起abc这是什么感觉?
What's it like,30abcyears with the same man?
我感觉很好 我希望他也是
Great for me. Good for him,I hope.
你觉得他不爱你?
You don't think he loves you?
他用他的方式来爱我
I think he always loved me in his way.
只不过不是"形影不离 情话绵绵"的方式罢了
Just not in the "spend time with me or showabcemotion or any affection for me"sort of way.
你为什么留在他身边?
Why did you stay?
我不需要他像我爱他一样爱我
I didn't need him to feel aboutabcme the way I did about him.
爱...不是...
Love... doesn't...
Charlotte?
我听过很多癌症病人不药而愈的故事
I've heard stories of cancer patientsabcgoing into spontaneous remission.
这会不会发生在我身上?
You think this might be that sorof thing?
不大可能 但谁知道呢
It's unlikely,but you never know.
如果我有多点时间...
If I just had a little more time...
我会好好陪Charlotteabc努力做个好丈夫
be with charlotte,tryabcand do better by her.
也许吧
Yeah,maybe.
你不相信我是真心的
You don't think I mean it.
我相信你是真心的
I think you mean it now.
说真心话比拿出实际行动要简单得多
I think it's much easier to meanabcit than to do anything about it.
心房壁几乎不动了 很抱歉
Chamber walls are barelyabcmoving. I'm sorry.
他需要一个朋友
He needs a friend.
我应付不了House和这件事
I can't... deal with this and house.
你也需要一个朋友
You need a friend too.
别把我的需要扯进去
You couldn't give a crap what I need.
你只是想有人盯紧他
You just want someone toabctake care of him.
他告诉Kutner的父母 这是他们的错
He told kutner'sabcparents it was their fault.
脾破裂 说明不是硬皮病
Ruptured spleen. Means it's not M.S.
你在这儿干什么?
What are you doing here?
等你把她的脾缝好后做活检abc看是不是风湿性关节炎
Waiting for you to fix her spleen so weabccan biopsy it for rheumatoid arthritis.
我做就行 回家去吧
I'll do it. Go home.
她不是你的病人
She's not your patient.
Kutner也不是我的朋友
And kutner wasn't my friend.
Kutner想死 Charlotte不想
Kutner wanted to die. Charlotte doesn't.
因此在我的衡量标准里 她更重要
So in a contest for myabcconcern and interest,she wins.
好吧 要么你是个冷血的混球abc要么是太痛苦以致无法面对
Okay,either you're a cold-hearted bastardabcor you're too miserable to face it.
回家大哭一场吧
Go home and cry.
不是风湿性关节炎 她的肝也有疤痕
It's not rheumatoidabcarthritis. Her liver's scarred.
不管她得了什么病 病情扩散了
Whatever she's got,it's spreading.
先澄清下 我无意冒犯abc一位已故同事的尊严
For the record,I'm uncomfortableabcviolating a dead colleague's dignity.
除非你找到什么 才算得上冒犯
It's only violatingabcit if you find something.
见到你真好
Good to see you.
你想找什么?
What are we looking for?
他在逃避
He was hiding.
为什么?
Why?
出于羞耻? 恐惧 你还好吧?
Shame? Fear? Are you okay?
你觉得难过也没关系的
It's okay not to be okay.
"殖民军战士镭射枪 编号11"
"Colonial warriorabcblaster. Number one one."
肯定是花几个月淘来的abc说明他对生活很有热情
He'd have spent months trackingabcthis down. He had passions.
显然他正陷于痛苦
He was obviously in pain.
原因真的那么重要吗?
Does it really matter why?
他把好的和不好的回忆挂在一起
He hung the bad with the good.
失去的和得到的并排放
His loss beside aabcreminder of what he'd gained.
说明他对痛苦很看得开
Means he was open about the pain.
如果痛苦加深 他没理由会隐瞒
Should mean that if it gotabcworse,he had no reason to hide it.
接下来这么办吧 House
Here's how we're gonna handle this,house.
我们离开这里 找间最近的酒吧abc边喝酒边聊天
We're gonna leave here and go to theabcclosest bar and drink and tell stories
聊聊Kutner当初怎么差点把手术室炸了
about the timeabckutner almost blew up an O.R.
发发牢骚 大醉一场
And pass out in our own sick.
这主意不错吧?
Sound like a plan?
我漏掉了什么?
What am I missing?
你这副表情又来了
You've got that look.
你又看出什么了
You figured this out.
你来这里 不是因为你关心Kutner
You're not here because youabccare about kutner.
而是因为这是一个谜
You're here because it's a mystery.
你要解开这个谜题
You're here for the puzzle.
会不会是 不是我漏了什么...
What if I didn't miss anything...
而是根本没什么可遗漏的?
'cause there's nothing to miss?
他并不是自杀 而是被人谋杀
He didn't kill himself. He was murdered.
会厌肌肉 脾脏 现在轮到肝
Epiglottis muscle,spleen,andabcnow her liver,
只剩余20%功能 仍在加速恶化
which is operating atabc20% and deteriorating fast.
自体免疫性肝炎?
Autoimmune hepatitis?
你呼Foreman了没?
Did you page foreman?
他接受了Cuddy让他休假的建议
Took up cuddy's offer of time off.
甲状腺激素水平正常 说明不是肝炎
Normal thyroid means no hepatitis.
可能是淀粉样变性abc淀粉堵塞攻击器官 组织--
Could be amyloidosis. Amyloidabcbuildup hits the organs,tissue--
解释不了肌肉萎缩
Her muscles wouldn't have atrophied.
你给丈夫做的超声如何?
You run the echo on the husband?
心脏持续衰竭 好转只是暂时的
Heart's still failing. Theabcimprovement was only temporary.
我比较喜欢简单的答法:abcHouse 你是对的
I prefer the less subtle answer:abcYou were right,house.
既然...不用花时间abc纠结丈夫为什么死不了
So...less time proving why hubby isn't dead.
就有更多时间研究Kutner为什么会死...
More time proving why kutner is.
谋杀动机
Motives for murder.
House...这是自杀abc警察已经调查过了
House... it was a suicide. Theabcpolice have already investigated.
他们只调查他们眼见的东西abc而忽略了看不到的
They investigated what theyabcsaw,not what they didn't saw.
去找他的朋友 同学 送比萨的人聊聊
Talk to friends,classmates,pizzaabcdelivery guy.
还有联系Foreman
And draft foreman.
- 他可以边抹眼泪边接电话abc- 不
- He can make calls through his tears.abc- No.
你这个"不" 是指"我才不要打给我男友
Is that no,I'm not calling my boyfriend,
谁叫他刚才打给我上司abc而不是我说他不回来"吗?
who apparently called my boss insteadabcof me to say he wasn't coming in?
真不公平 凭什么你一个音节abc里头能包含这么多潜台词?
'Cause it's really not fair to haveabcthat much subtext in one syllable.
我们都想知道 为什么Kutner这么做
We all wanna know why kutner did it.
但我们不想浪费时间去纠缠鬼魂
But we're not gonna wasteabctime chasing ghosts.
你们一点不好奇吗?
You're not remotely curious?
我只好奇为什么一个崇尚理性的人abc忽然变得不理智了
Only why a man who embraces the rationalabcis suddenly pursuing the irrational.
她可能得了α1-抗胰蛋白酶缺乏症
She could haveabcalpha-1anti-trypsin deficiency.
给她做个α1抗胰蛋白酶测试
Run her aat proteins.
我想和Eddie在一起
I'd like to be with eddie.
你才做完手术不久
It's too soon after your surgery.
你死后可以指定把器官捐给某个人 对吧?
You can ask that someone getabcyour organs if you die,right?
即便器官银行不批准?
Even if the donor bank turned them down?
个人捐赠者可以绕过登记程序abc但还有很多因素要考虑...
Individual donors can bypass the registry,butabcthere are a lot of other factors...
- 比如血型--abc- 我给他输过血
- blood type-- -abcI've given him blood.
- 不只是--abc- 求你了
- It's notabcjust-- - Please.
如果我先走一步abc我想你把我的心脏给他
If I go before him,I wantabcyou to give him my heart.
治疗还没结束呢
This isn't over yet.
我还有得治
For me.
可他没别的指望了 不是吗?
T it is for him,isn't it?
是的
Yes.
Remy Hadley 也可以叫我13
Remy hadley. I also answer to thirteen.
有时会和你上床
I sometimes sleep with you.
我知道我应该打给你
I know I should have called.
- 我只是需要点时间abc- 一个人?
- I just need some time.abc- Alone?
我这辈子经历了很多困难
I've worked through a lotabcof bad stuff in my life.
都一个人撑过来了
Always done it solo.
那我走好了
So I should go.
- 对不起abc- 没什么
- I'm sorry.abc- Okay.
信息部门准备关闭Kutner的电邮账号
I.T.'S been trying to closeabcout kutner's email account.
显然有人还登陆着
Apparently,someone's stillabclogged onto it.
不难猜到密码是kutner
It wasn't hard to figureabcout that his password was kutner.
他做了他们不让你做的事
He did what they tell you not to.
- 他不是被谋杀的abc- 他父母是
- He wasn't murdered.abc- But his parents were.
杀了他们的人就要假释了
And the guy who killedabcthem is coming up for parole.
他是要假释了
He's coming up for parole.
不是已经出来了
He's not o on parole.
Kutner在每个听证会上都作了供
Kutner testified at everyabcone of his hearings.
他不是唯一在计算时间的人
The guy wouldn't be theabcfirst to see the clock ticking.
他是被自己的枪杀死的
He was killed by his own gun.
出于防卫目的 在几年前买的
Which he bought yearsabcago,obviously for self-defense.
太阳穴 警察发现了火药残留
In the temple. Cops found residue.
凶手从没想过把它弄得像自杀--
Right,the murderer would neverabctry to make it look like suicide--
这太不道德了
that would be unethical.
你没问病人的事
You haven't asked about my patient.
你在等α-1抗胰蛋白酶的结果
You're waiting on aat protein results.
就是说你查过我是不是还关注病人
Means you checked up toabcsee that I'm still on it.
你想把病人转给别人 但又没有
You wanna transferabcthe case,but you won't
因为你认为这是唯一abc能让我集中精力的事
because you think it's the onlyabcthing that's holding me together.
放轻松 我是对是错 很快就知道了
Relax. Either I'm right or I'mabcwrong. We'll know soon enough.
找到这个病人的病因...
Find what's killing your patient...
我会再给你下一个病人
and then I'll find you another patient.
怎么回事?
What happened?
护士发现她的
Nurses found her like this.
她从推车上抓到什么 就注射进身体
She broke into the cart andabcinjected whatever she could grab.
做傻事 让自己情况比Eddie更糟
Dumb way to look worse for eddie.
她不是想让自己更糟
She wasn't trying to look worse.
她是想自杀
She was trying to kill herself.
现在稳定了 但她的肝彻底停止工作
She's stable,but whatever was leftabcof her liver is definitely shot now.
Eddie也没什么变化
And there's no change in eddie.
那...感谢这个白痴般的行为
So...thanks to her idiotic move,
找不到新肝脏的话abc二十四小时内她就会死
she's dead in 24 hours ifabcshe doesn't get a new ler.
这是无私 她很爱他
It was selfless. She loves him.
这和我说的有冲突吗?
How does that disagree withabcwhat I just said?
α-1抗胰蛋白酶缺乏检查呈阴性
Test was negative for aat deficiency.
可能是骨髓纤维变性abc但检查至少要四十八小时
Myelofibrosis fits,butabctesting takes at least 48 hours.
得试试活体部分捐赠
We should try a partial donationabcfrom a live donor.
损伤太严重了 她需要一整个肝
Damage is too severe. Sheabcneeds a whole new liver.
没有诊断结果 没有肝脏
No diagnosis,no liver.
没有肝脏 活不下去
No liver,no living.
你怎么知道?
What do you know?
这就是骨髓纤维变性
It is myelofrosis.
这儿写着呢
Says so right here.
谁去给Cuddy说?
Who wants to tell cuddy?
你对移植委员会撒过多少次谎了?
How many times have you lied toabcthe transplant committee?
- 就两次abc- 几次有用的?
- Just twice.abc- How many times has it worked?
我...看不出来这有什么联系
I... don't quite see how that's relevant.
住手 警察来了
Cheese it. It's the coppers.
在你执着于调查Kutner的时候abc我们不会放任他们死去
We're not just gonna leave themabcto die while you fixate on kutner.
技术上说 他不是我们的病人
Technically,he's not our patient.
所以我只是任她死了
So I'm really only leaving her to die.
通常情况我们已经想过了
We've already explored the usual options.
不再考虑下罕见的情况吗?
Shouldn't we at leastabcexplore unusual ones?
当然 别担心 上帝给了我两只耳朵
Absolutely. Don't worry. Thisabcis why god gave me two ears.
Kutner会说 让我们对Cuddy坦白
Kutner would say we should justabccome clean with cuddy.
如果他在这儿的话
If only he were here to say that.
我确定Cuddy一定会偏向那个老家伙
I'm sure cuddy wouldabcbe bound to fall for the old,
"嗨 死人不会介意我们--"
"hey,the dead guy won'tabcmind if we're wasting--"
需要一个无可救药浪漫主义者说服另一个
Need an incurable romantic toabctalk to incurable romantic.
Kutner不是被谋杀的
Kutner wasn't murdered.
你是伴着那首"Who"摘下墨镜abc推论出来的吧?(CSI)
You deduce that by removing yourabcsun glasses to the strains of a who song?
自杀意味着你原本能帮他abc谋杀就不是你的责任
Suicide means you could have helpedabchim. Murder lets you off the hook.
说肝脏肝脏到
Needs a liver. Has a liver.
他能部分捐赠
He can make a partial donation.
他越快同意 她越快逃过死神
The faster he agrees,theabcfaster she gets to not die.
部分不够 她要整个肝
Partial won't be enough.abcShe needs a whole liver.
而他会死于手术
And he'd never survive the procedure.
真对仗啊?
Nice symmetry,huh?
要是他在手术中死去 你就有一整个肝了
He dies on the table,andabcyou give her his whole liver.
如果他会 那也是为了爱
If he's gonna do this,he'sabcgonna do this for love.
我想他得和说同种语言的人交流
I thought he should talkabcto someone who spoke the language.
你想我死在手术台上
You want me to die on the table.
不是我们想
We don't want you to.
是你妻子需要
Your wife needs you to.
我的心脏呢?
My heart?
快要不行了 你最多还有几天
Is still dying. You haveabca couple days at most.
但这时间足够救她
But this could buyabcuse enough time to save her.
我什么时候对她说再见?
When can I say good-bye?
你不能
You can't.
如果她知道了这个 你认为她会同意吗?
If she knew what weabcwere planning,would she be okay?
她会恨我
She'll resent me.
她会活下来 其他的都不重要
She'll be alive. Nothing else matters.
不能进行移植
You can't do the transplant.
除非他说不
Only if he said no.
但你这样急说明他同意了
But your urgentabchovering means he said yes.
他的手指有结节 可能他的医生诊断错了
His fingers have nodules. Iabcthink his doctors misdiagnosed him.
或是你想得太美好了
Or you sprinkled tooabcmuch wishful thinking in your tea.
肥胖者伴有肺癌--很容易解释心衰
Obese man with lung cancer-- two easyabcexplanations for his heart failure.
但结节说明是另外的 可治愈的
No dules can mean somethingabcelse,somethg curable.
回急诊室去
Go back to the E.R.
感谢你和你的怯懦
My thanks to you and your cold feet.
怎么? 我让你去告诉好消息--
What's going on?I'm givingabcyou a shot at a cool result--
甚至是让你嘲笑别的医生的机会
better yet,a chance toabcprove other doctors idiotic.
除了你是错的
Except you're wrong.
你也是伴着那首"Who"摘下墨镜时abc推论出来的?
You figure that out by taking f yourabcsunglasses to the strains of a who song?
杀了Kutner父母的人abc两个月前死于动脉瘤
The guy who killed kutner's parentsabcdied of an aneurism two months ago.
Kutner没说过
Kutner hid from everyone.
你没有机会救他--没人有
You didn't get a chance toabcsave him--no one did.
去检查 看你是不是有机会救Eddie
Run the tests. Find out ifabcyou have a chance to save eddie.
坏消息
Bad news.
爱救不了你
Love can't save you.
另外...
On the other hand...
霉可以
mold can.
你的心衰是由一种叫心脏芽生菌的abc真菌感染导致
Your heart failure was caused by a fungalabcinfection called cardiac blastomycosis.
最初是在肺部结节 每个医生abc除了一个 都当成了癌症
It started as nodules in your lungs whichabcevery doc,except one,mistook for cancer.
很罕见 可治愈
It's very rare,very curable.
给你用抗真菌药
I'm starting you on itraconazole.
但我怎么没吃药都好起来了?
But how come I was getting betterabcwithout the medicine?
你的情绪让儿茶酚胺分泌增加abc促进催乳激素的分泌
Your emotional state bumped your catecholaminesabcwhich helped raise your prolactin.
情绪?
My emotional state?
三个月治疗 你就能变得健康强壮
Three months of treatment,you'llabcbe back to your buff,chiseled self.
我不想治疗
I don't want the treatment.
做移植
Do the transplant.
但你这是在...
But you'd be trading...
放弃肯定能活的机会abc换取她不一定能活的机会
the certainty that you'll live forabcthe uncertainty that she'll live.
反正我都准备死了
I was ready to di anyway.
那就对你下个妻子好点
Now you get to beabcnicer to your next wife.
如果你不干...就让我出院
If you won't do it... release me.
如果我被车撞了 停在了太平间
And when I get hit by a carabcand show up in your morgue,
你就能把我的肝脏给她了
you can give her my liver then.
这本质上是要我们去杀人
You're basically askingabcus to commit murder.
昨天的计划不也一样
I was yesterday too.
他还有二十年性命和两天是不一样的
There's a difference when he has 20abcyears to live instead of two days.
事实上和上法律都无区别
Not really. Not legally.
这就是你说服我们的方法abc说它不是背德的?
That's your way of convincing us toabcdo this,by saying it's no more immoral?
那蠢货不管怎样都会做的
The idiot is gonna doabcthis with or without us.
只是这样能保存器官
This way we can protect the organ.
我们要保护他
We should be protecting him.
那就把他绑在床上 等他妻子死去?
So we strap him to theabcbed,wait till his wife dies?
我不干
I'm not doing this.
我去
I will.
已经有了一个人毫无意义地死了
We've already had one pointless death.
Eddie... 这怎么回事?
Eddie... what's going on?
不知道 他把我推过来的
I don't know. He just came and got me.
你丈夫的病能治好 但他想要死abc好把肝脏给你
Your husband has a curable disease,but heabcwants to die so he can give you his liver.
你能接受这个 还是想让他接受治疗?
Are you okay with that,or wouldabcyou rather he take the treatment?
你个混球!
You son of a bitch!
- Eddie 不!abc- 让我干
- Eddie,don't!abc- You have to let me do this.
Chaotte 能听见我说话吗?
Chaotte,can you hear me?
她发烧了 穿刺显示她的白血球过高
She spiked a fever. Lp showsabcher white cells through the roof.
她全身感染
She's infected everywhere.
我真该炒了你
I should fire you.
我只是完成你没做到的事
Just did what youabcfailed to do--
说服Eddie活着 让他妻子死去
convince eddie toabclive and let his wife die.
感染意味着新线索
Infection means we have a new clue.
顶多还有两三个小时来诊断
A a full two or three hoursabcto figure it out.
肉状瘤病会导致脾和肝的损伤
Sarcoidosis hits theabcspleen and the liver.
那肺就该有问题
She would have lung issues.
硬皮病会使组织发炎红肿
Scleroder ma inflames the tissue.
皮肤和胃肠道都没有问题
No skin or gi problems.
- 她隐藏了些什么?abc- 你不知道...
- What is she hiding?abc- You don't know--
要么我们有所有线索但我们是白痴abc要么就是还没有掌握所有的线索
Either we have all the clues and we'reabcidiots or we don't have all the clues.
可能的暴露源 接触过的人 去过的地方
Possible exposure,people,places.
都是
Both.
好糟糕的谎言
Bad lie.
你真的觉得夏威夷的海滩abc和里约热内卢的是一样的吗?
Did you really think the beaches inabchawaii were just like the beaches in rio?
携带的病菌沙蝇就是截然不同的
The disease bearing sandabcflies are completely different.
她从没去过里约热内卢
She's never been to rio.
你和谁一起去的?
Who'd you go with?
你为什么要这么做?
Why are you doing this?
我不是真的需要知道是谁
I don't actually need to know who it was.
我只是要确认你去过...
I just need to know that you went...
这样我们就能知道你有内脏利什曼病
so we can know that youabchave visceral leishmaniasis.
但既然Lancelot都已经愿意为你而死了...abc(亚瑟王圆桌武士中的第一位勇士)
But since lancelot therewasabcready to die for you...
他大概两个答案都想知道
he might wantthe answer to both.
去年...
Last year...
那个人你不认识的
it was nobody you knew.
该是我们一起去里约热内卢的
Rio was supposed to be ours.
但我厌倦等待了
I got tired of waiting.
对不起
I'm so sorry.
给她用锑
Start her on antimony.
还有 让Cuddy给她找个肝脏
And have cuddy find her a liver.
他们准备为对方死
They were ready to die...
是缘于负罪感 而不是爱
but for guilt,not love.
没有爱你不会感到这么沉重的负罪感
You can't feel thatabcmuch guilt without love.
纽约慈济医院的直升机abc正带着肝脏赶来
New york mercy's medevacing the liver.
- 到达的时间大概是...abc- 告诉他们转向回去
- It should be here...abc- Tell 'em to turn around.
Charlotte的治疗没有起效
Charlotte's treatment isn't taking.
我们确诊得太晚了
We diagnosed it too late.
别人都去参加Kutner的葬礼了
Everyone's headingabcover to kutner's funeral.
你可以和我一起去
You're welcome to ride with me.
我打算留在Charlotte身边
I'm gonna stay with charlotte.
她给你争取了一些救Eddie的时间
She bought you some time to save eddie.
这会给她的死带来一些意义
It'll give her death some meaning.
不 不会的
No. It won'T.
我看错你了
I w wrong about you.
- 不 你没有abc- 你很痛苦
- No,you weren't.abc- You're in pain.
你再一次把这事想得太人性了
And you're romanticizing... again.
你和他天天在一起工作两年了abc你从来没有预计到这会发生
You worked with him every day for twoabcyears,and you never saw this coming.
没有人预计到
No one saw it coming.
但是你会预计到所有事
But you see everything coming.
这从来都不是关于你遗漏了什么
This has never been aboutabcwhat you missed.
是关于你为什么会遗漏
This is about why you missed it.
你害怕你失去你的天赋 迷失...
You're terrified that you'reabclosing your gift,losing...
迷失你自己
who you are.
我很害怕 你在迷失后会做什么
And I'm terrified of what you'd do then.
除非你觉得在这给我做治疗更重要...
Unless you feel there'sabcmore to do here to cure me...
你不是有一场葬礼要去参加吗?
don't you have a funeral to go to?
* 我 搭车离开
* I'm taking a ride off to one side
* 这是我自己的事
* it is a personal thing
* 我已不能忍受
* where when I can't stand
* 困在笼子里 我并不后悔
* up in this cage I'm not regretting
* 我不需要得到更多
* I don't need a better thing
* 少一点刚好
* I'll settle for less
* 这对我是另一回事
* it's another thing for me
* 我只想徜徉过这个世界
* I just have toabcwander through this world
* 独自一人
* alone
* 停 别掉进
* stop before you fall
* 我挖好的坑里
* into the hole that I have dug here
* 歇着 就算你
* rest,even as you
*开始感受到我的感受
* are startin' to feel the way I used to
* 我不需要得到更多
* I don't need a better thing
* 我只是有些困惑
* just to sound confused
* 别说个不停
* don't talk about everyone
* 你没法让我开心起来
* I am not amused by you
* 因为我要失去你了
* 'cause I'm gonna lose ya
* 要失去你了
* yes,I'm gonna lose ya
* 如果我就要失去你
* if I'm gonna lose ya
* 因为我要失去你了
* 'cause I'm gonna lose ya
* 要失去你了
* yes,I'm gonna lose ya
* 如果我就要失去你
* if I'm gonna lose ya
* 那就永远失去你吧
* I'll lose you now for good